本字幕由YYeTs人人影视翻译制作
更多美剧字幕 请登陆 www.YYeTs.net
■
翻译：小松狮      校对：小路     时间轴：虫不知
特效：Will      后期：冰河       监制：蛐蛐
■
这些人
These people.
太可悲了
Pathetic.
我早就看过这个了
I already read that one anyway.
克兰曼的杂志比这里好多了
Kleinman has better magazines.
其实你们不用都来的
You know, you guys really don't need to hang around.
下周才会出检查结果
We won't even get the results till next week.
兄弟  我们当然要来  别开玩笑了
Buddy, we're going to be here. You kidding me?
是全套的正电子电脑断层扫描吗
It is a full PET/CT, correct?
确实是全套的  不只是正电子发射断层扫描
You definitely want the PET/CT and not just the PET.
是正电子电脑断层扫描
It's a PET/CT.
很好  你要的就是那个
Good. That's what you want.
因为有些地方会偷工减料
Some places skimp,
有时候他们只做正电子发射断层扫描
And they only do the PET.
我不会点名道姓  但是
I'm not naming any names, but...
我只是搞不懂你们为什么不去克兰曼
I just still don't understand why you don't go to Kleinman.
可是沃尔特的主治医生在这里
This is where Walt's doctor is.
但是在我们医院做  你们就不用
With us, you wouldn't have to wait
等到下星期才拿报告
until next week to get the results.
对不起  但是这些扫描图并不难解读
I'm sorry, but these scans are not that difficult to read.
我只要看一眼沃尔特的扫描图
I could take one look at Walt's
就能立刻知道他的情况
And tell you immediately how he's doing.
真的不用了
Really.
医生总喜欢让人觉得  他们比技术人员聪明
Doctors like people to think that they're so much smarter
但他们录入病人信息的时候
Than the technicians, but you would be surprised
不知道要问我们多少问题
How much they come to us for input.
我得去上个厕所
Never turn down a chance to hit the bathroom, huh?
不好意思
Excuse me.
你没事吧
You all right in there?
你还好吗
You okay?
很好  谢谢
I'm fine, thank you.
先生  你可以去更衣室换衣服了
Sir, you can go back to your changing room and get dressed.
我做得怎么样
So, how'd we do?
你做得很好
You did fine.
-看见什么了吗  -我只是个技术员  怀特老师
- See anything? - I'm just a technician, Mr. White.
戴尔克沃利医生下周会通知你检查的结果
Dr. Delcavoli will go over the results with you next week.
抱歉
Sorry.
绝
命
毒
师
第二季
第九集
事实上  洗钱还是挺容易的
Actually, the money laundering aspect is fairly straightforward.
但是要记住一点  不要告诉你妻子
But I gotta tell ya, the not-telling-your-wife aspect...
一下子变得有钱  多数人都会有怀疑
Most people want to know why they suddenly got rich.
她要发现的话  也是在我死后了
If she finds out, it's after I'm gone.
他们说你还有多少时间
How much time they giving you?
几星期吧
Weeks.
可能
Maybe.
太遗憾了
Sorry to hear it.
我还希望我们能合作赚大钱
I was hoping we could make some real money together.
我们来算算帐
Oh, well. Let's crunch some numbers.
我们要洗多少钱
How much money are we laundering?
这次16000美元
At this time, $16,000.
你干这个有多久了
How long have you been doing this?
我们刚刚出了状况
We've had some extenuating circumstances.
当然
Apparently.
好的  16000
All right, 16,000
洗钱要打75折
Laundered at 75 cents on the dollar,
减去我的劳务费
Minus my fee,
17%
Which is 17%,
一共是9960美元  恭喜你
Comes to $9,960. Congratulations.
你给家人留下了一辆二手速霸路车
You just left your family a secondhand Subaru.
我们会制更多毒  很多很多
We'll just have to cook more, a lot more.
那正是我的律师意见
That's my legal opinion.
趁热打铁  抓紧时间
Make hay while the sun is still shining.
我们这个周末应该安排点节目
You know, we should do something this weekend.
好让我们别去想检查结果
Get our minds off the test results?
事实上  我
Actually, I...
我在想该去看看妈妈
I'm thinking I should go see Mom.
我从来没给她打过电话
You know, I never did call her.
你觉得
You're expecting the...
扫描的结果会不好
The news from the scan to be bad.
天哪  沃尔特
God. Walt.
我需要你跟我一起积极乐观面对
I need you to stay positive with me here.
我是的
I am.
乐观积极很好
Positive is good.
我很乐观  但是乐观不能改变事实
I'm all for positive, but positive doesn't change facts.
懂吗
All right?
不改变我们需要做好准备的事实
It doesn't change the need to be prepared.
我知道
I know.
我只是想给自己希望
I'm just trying to be hopeful, okay?
原谅我
You know? Forgive me.
听着
Look,
我想知道妈妈是否会留给你点东西  如果
I need to know Mom's going to leave you something if...
如果我不在了
If I'm no longer around.
我只是想去直接问问她  仅此而已
I just need to get that straight. That's all.
相信我  我会竭尽全力为你争取的
And believe me, I'm going to earn every penny of it, too.
整天抱怨服侍她的护士
Complaining about her nurses the entire time.
"胡妮安塔把我的烟灰缸藏起来了"
"Juanita is hiding my ashtray."
然后发表30分钟的
A 30-minute discourse about
关于糖袋子的突然失踪的长篇大论
How the sugar packets are suddenly disappearing.
她一天到晚在唠叨那些东西
And, oh, she's counting every one of them. You know?
要是我能插上嘴就不错了
I'll be lucky if I get a word in edgewise.
我反而觉得扫描的结果会很好
I actually think the news from the scan is going to be good.
可能你也该有个心理准备
Perhaps you should prepare for that.
我们得干点什么
We should do something.
没错
Yeah, we should.
不是  干点别的
No, something else.
我们应该出去玩
We should go somewhere.
你去过乔治娅·欧基夫博物馆吗
Have you been to the Georgia O'Keeffe Museum?
展览原子弹的地方吗
Is that the one with the A-bombs?
乔治娅·欧基夫
Georgia O'Keeffe.
她是个画家
She's a painter.
你从没听说过乔治娅·欧基夫吗
You've never heard of Georgia O'Keeffe?
谁
Who is it?
你该上点课了
Boy, you need some educating.
我是要  快来
Yes, I do. Come here.
我们起来去圣达菲吧  玩上一整天
Why don't we go up to Santa Fe? We'll make a day of it.
你想要开一整天车去圣达菲就为博物馆吗
You want to go all the way to Santa Fe for a museum?
没错  我们要出发了  快起来
Yep, we're going. Get up.
不能看场电影  或者玩玩碰碰车吗
Why can't we just go to the movies or putt-putt?
博物馆太无聊了
It's the shit.
让你熏陶点文化又不会死
A little culture won't kill you.
你可能会喜欢的
Besides, you might like it.
很多她的画都像是阴道
A lot of her paintings look like vaginas.
真的
Really?
还有麦片吗
Is there still cereal?
如果我认识你  就留个言
If I know you, leave a message.
你到底在哪里  快接电话
Where the hell are you? Pick up the phone.
-杰西  快接电话  -等等  等等
- Hello, Jesse. Pick up...  - Hold on, hold on.
抱歉  稍等
Sorry. One sec.
怎么了
What?
我一直在打你电话  你手机上呢
I've been trying to reach you. Where's your drop phone?
-我有事在忙  -取消你的所有活动
- I've been busy. - Clear your social calendar.
-我们得制毒  -什么  今天
- We have to cook. - What? Today?
不是  但至少今天你得去采购
No. You'll need today at least to gather supplies.
我们需要全新的玻璃器皿  球形加热器
Now, we're going to need all new glassware, heating mantles,
大约能制100磅的冰毒
About a hundred pounds of ice.
你有纸和笔吗
Do you have a paper and pencil?
你该写下来
You should be writing this down.
你自己去买吧  我今天有事
Go shopping yourself. I got plans.
抽大麻  吃奇多  手淫
Smoking marijuana, eating Cheetos, and masturbating
在我的字典里可不算什么事
Do not constituteplans in my book.
去你的  伙计
Screw you and your book, man.
我要去圣达菲的博物馆  不用告诉你
I'm going to a museum in Santa Fe, not like you need to know.
你去博物馆
You're going to a museum?
乔治娅·欧基夫
Georgia O'Keeffe.
她是个画家
She's a painter? Duh?
画些阴道画
She does these vagina pictures.
或是别的什么
Or paintings, or...
或者画过  我不知道
Or just painted. I don't know.
你到底在说什么
What are you even talking about?
我的事干嘛要跟你说
Why am I explaining myself to you?
我做什么不管你的事
It's none of your damn business what I'm doing.
你要知道的就是
All you need to know is
我今天不会制毒  买东西或干类似的事
I ain't cooking, shopping or whatever.
我来解释给你听
Let me explain something to you.
你和我必须要一直制毒到下周二
You and I need to cook through to next Tuesday.
周二  连着四天
Tuesday? Four days straight?
不管你喜不喜欢  我们别无选择
Like it or not, we have no choice.
那到底为什么
And why, exactly, is that?
我们的甲胺  快变质了
Our methylamine. It's going bad.
-什么  -会慢慢失去化学反应能力
- What? - It's losing its chemical potency.
除非你想再去偷一桶
Now, unless stealing another barrel sounds good to you...
见鬼的  当然不
Hell, no.
那我们就必须在它变质前抓紧制毒
We have to act fast before it goes to waste.
有笔和纸吗
You have a paper and pencil?
-快点  -好了  说吧
- Come on. - All right, all right. Go.
我还是希望你别去了
I wish you didn't have to do this.
我也不想去啊
Me, too.
我会尽快回来
But I'll be back before you know it,
如果需要我  就打电话
And you can always call if you need me.
还要冒险和你妈妈讲话吗
And risk talking to your mother?
那可要是紧急事件了
That'd have to be some emergency.
爱你
Love you.
路上小心
Fly safe, okay?
你居然把制毒室开到机场来
You brought a meth lab to the airport?
怎么  你说要快点  这不省了一趟路
What? You said we were in a hurry. I saved us a trip.
所有东西都买好了吗  六样东西
Did you get everything? All six?
带回流冷凝器的吗
With reflux condensers?
没错
Yes, like I said.
那快走  开车啊
Just go. Drive. Go, go.
你也早上好  伙计
Good morning to you, too, man.
-太傻了  -三大袋洋葱圈
- Stupid... - Three entire bags of Funyuns?
怎么  洋葱圈很好吃
What? Funyuns are awesome.
-天哪  -没有给我的吗
- God. - More for me.
没有含蛋白质的吗
How about something with some protein, maybe?
健康食品
Something green, huh?
天哪  我手机没信号
Man, I'm getting no service.
你是怎么活着的
How are you even alive?
唷  看看你手机
Yo, check your phone.
有信号吗
You get any bars?
有一格
I've got a signal.
让我用下你手机吧
Let me use yours, would ya?
绝对不行
Absolutely not.
我得考虑到斯凯勒会查我的通讯记录
I have to assume Skyler checks my phone records. You know that.
-不是生意上的事  私人电话  -私人
- It's not business. It's personal. - Oh, personal.
-女的吗  -有可能
- What, female? - Maybe.
当然是  我猜就是
Absolutely, that's all I need.
斯凯勒重播号码  然后发现是脱衣舞女
Skyler hits "redial" and some stripper answers.
听着  她才不是脱衣舞娘  好吗  伙计
Look, she's not a stripper. Okay, dickwad?
我妻子会检查的
My wife checks.
饮用水吗
Drinking water?
就这些吗
Is that all we've got?
10加仑
Ten gallons?
怎么  你还打算在里面洗澡吗
What, you planning on taking a bath in it?
天哪
Oh, God.
别放那里  那是我们的工作台
Not there. That is our work station.
-工作台  -没错
- Our work station.  - That's right.
你干嘛不找个不会掉的地方放好
Why don't you try to find a place where it won't get lost?
考虑到这是我们唯一的一串钥匙
Considering this is our only set
我们现在还身处荒野
And we are a million miles from nowhere.
你怎么不把钥匙粘在你的屁股旁边
Why don't you try sticking them up your ass sideways?
2.35磅
2.35 pounds.
2.35
2.35.
这是最后一包了
That's the last of it.
总共多少
How many total?
19包
19.
按钱算呢
Dollar-wise?
多少
How much?
重量中间数  是2.2磅
Well, median weight... 2.2 pounds.
一共41.8磅
That's 41.8,
算是42磅  我们最近卖多少钱
Call it 42 pounds at... What are we selling it for these days?
-4万一磅  -四万美元吗
- 40 a pound. - $40,000?
是你说要涨价的
You said raise the prices.
好的  40乘以42
All right, that's 40 times 42,
减掉分成的钱
Minus distribution charges.
多少
What?
67200美元
$672,000.
总共吗
All that?
每人
Each?
Each.
-每人六十  - 七万两千美元
- Six hundred and... - Seventy-two thousand dollars each.
太好了
Hell, yeah!
高兴点  宝贝  快来
Come high, baby! Come on!
发电机的声音
Well, there goes the generator.
我猜是没汽油了
I think that's it for the gas.
时间正好  唷
Perfect timing, yo.
你怎么知道
How do you figure that?
你什么意思  我们已经弄完了
What do you mean? We're done cooking.
要到甲胺用完为止
I am not done until this barrel is empty.
我来看一下
Look at that.
我们还有10或者12加仑的甲胺
I'd say we still got 10, 12 gallons of methylamine.
别这样  你的野心到哪里去了
Come on, where's your ambition?
上帝啊  你是认真的吗
Jesus. Seriously?
我们已经超额完成了
We are way ahead of schedule.
而且发电机也没汽油了  丙烷也快没了
Plus, the genny needs gas, we're almost out of propane,
而且在这破地方呆得我背快痛死了
And my back is killing me from that piece-of-crap cot.
我们能不能至少休息一个晚上
Come on, can we at least just take the night off.
星期二之前你也不用回去  对吗
Look, I don't have to take you back till Tuesday, right?
我们明天再来
So we come back tomorrow,
再继续搞这些玻璃东西
Strap on the sizzle and glass up the rest.
就这样吧
Come on!
周围总会有个小旅馆什么的
There's got to be a Denny's out there someplace.
看看篮球
Grand Slam?
洗个热水澡
A hot shower?
分开住
Separate rooms.
那是条件
That's a given.
没电了
The battery's dead.
我叫你把钥匙放在安全的地方
Back when I asked you to put the keys in a safe place,
你放哪里了
Where did you put them?
我插在了点火器上
I left them right here in the ignition.
狗娘养的
Son of a bitch.
这不是我的错  警报器坏了
This is not my fault. The buzzer didn't buzz.
-什么  -警报器
- The what? - The buzzer.
你把钥匙插进去的时候
It buzzes when you put the keys in
警报器会响  提醒你电池开着
To let you know that the battery's on.
我知道  但是没报警
I know that. It didn't buzz.
听着  我没有转钥匙  我不笨
Look, I didn't turn the key or anything. I'm not stupid.
你听到报警了吗
Did you hear the buzzer buzz?
这是机械故障
It's faulty. It's a faulty mechanism.
这毛病是遗传的  还是你天生的
Is this a genetic thing with you? Is it congenital?
婴儿的时候  你妈是不是打过你的头
Did your mother drop you on your head when you were a baby?
警报器坏了
The buzzer did not buzz,
而且是你一开始让我把钥匙放好的
And you made me move the keys in the first place,
-记得吗  -我明白你的意思了
- Remember? - I see your point.
你低能到  我必须要告诉你
Your imbecility being what it is, I should have known to say,
别让钥匙插在点火器里整整两天
"Don't leave the keys in the ignition the entire two days!"
我原来是要放在柜子上的  白痴
I wanted to leave them on the counter, bitch!
对不起  应该是工作台
Oh, I'm sorry. The work station.
我们得想办法充电
All right, so we need to jump the battery somehow.
怎么弄
OK. How?
你没事吧
You going to be okay?
该死
Damn it.
什么味道
What's it taste like?
糟透了吗
Bad, huh?
好的  就放这里
This is good. Right here.
给  红的接红  黑的接黑
Here. Red to red, black to black.
正极  负极
Positive, negative.
好了  发动
All right. Start it up.
这东西怎么回事
The hell's wrong with this thing?
你得用力拉
You have to really pull.
我在用力
I am.
用力气  别像个娘儿们
Really pull. Not like a girl.
我正在拉  要么你自己来
You know what? Pull this. I am pulling.
这玩意儿也需要一点热身
It just needs to warm up a little.
上帝啊
Oh, Jesus.
干得好
Well done.
跟往常一样  就只会
As always. Just...
干得好
Well done.
上帝啊
God.
快点啊  他妈的
Come on, you bitches.
信号快来啊
Hear me now.
妈的
Damn it!
太傻了
This is stupid.
我们现在必须要用你的手机了
Okay, now we have to use your phone.
这东西毁了  明白吗  毁了
This is ruined. Do you understand? Just ruined.
我知道你把线接错了  所以爆炸了
I understand you hooked it up wrong and you blew it up.
-不是这样的  -你怎么知道
- That is not what happened. - How do you know?
把我们最后点水倒上去的可不是我
I wasn't the one who dumped out the last of our water.
就我所知的就这些
That's what I know.
着火了  抱歉我没有考虑周到
There was a fire. Excuse me for thinking on my feet.
那就是你想的吗
Is that... You were thinking.
现在我们来搞清楚状况
Now that we have identified the problem.
你和你那愚蠢的想法  那才是问题所在
You and thinking, that's the problem.
听着  必须得有人来接我们
Look, somebody is going to have to pick us up.
你妻子是不会注意到一个小电话的
Your wife is not going to notice one little call.
怀特老师  快点
Mr. White, come on.
好的  听着
All right, look.
干脆一点  别说废话
Make it snappy.
-漫游很费电的  -好的
- The roaming drains the battery. - All right.
唷  瘦子
Yo, Skinny, hey.
听着  你必须马上来接我们
Listen, I need you to come pick us up.
现在  好吗  我们被困在这儿了
Now, all right? We're stuck out here.
你有笔吗  写下方向
You got a pen for directions?
铅笔当然行  别磨叽
A pencil's fine, retard.
能写字的就行  没关系
Just something to write with. It doesn't matter.
好的  准备好了吗
All right, so you ready?
你要延着40号公路向西
So you're going to head west on the 40 for,
开大约30里
Like, what, 30 miles?
你会经过一个赌场
And you're just gonna go past the casino
停车场上有个大箭头的
With the big arrows in the parking lot.
大箭头  超级大的那种
Big arrows, giant arrows.
会闪的那种  你肯定能看见
They light up and blink and shit. You can't miss them.
然后你得减速
But then you're gonna want to take it slow
右边会有条泥路
Because there's this dirt road right
路口会有个写着3的白牌子
Before this white sign with a 3 on it, okay?
然后你就沿着路开  进入郊区
Now, you're going to be way, way out in the boonies, okay?
非常非常远
Like, crazy far, so you just got to
你要一直沿着那条泥路开
Keep heading down that dirt road for what?
大概15英里
About another 15 miles.
真的那么远
Really? That far?
快点  会没电的
Hurry up. The battery.
沿着路开  大概15英里
Just go down that road for, like, 15 more miles.
我们离公路远着呢
I mean, we're way the hell out here.
唷  听着
And yo, listen.
带点水来
Bring water.
现在就出发
Leave now.
他来了
He's coming.
探索频道放过有个人
There was this guy on the Discovery Channel
爬山的时候摔断了腿
Who broke his leg mountain biking,
还要喝自己的尿来求生
And he had to drink urine for,
直到护林员找到他
You know, just until the forest ranger found him.
他说尿尝起来很烫
He said it tasted like really hot,
像以前的苏打水
Really old soda.
我们应该打电话
We should just call.
我会讲得很快的
You know? I'll be quick. Just be like,
唷  你在哪里
"Yo, where are you?"
好吧
All right.
快点
Come on.
唷  你在哪里
Yo, where are you?
你看见白牌子了吗
So you saw the white sign?
他快来了
He's almost here.
伙计
Oh, man.
我们真的快疯了
We're getting really freaked out.
好的  那你现在在泥路上了吗
All right, so you're on the dirt road?
他在泥路上了  很好
He's on the dirt road. Good.
你刚刚过了河
You just crossed the river?
-你看见什么东西了吗  -等等  什么河
- Have you seen anything? - Wait, wait. What river?
什么河  你在说什么  伙计
What river? What the hell river you talking about, man?
没有河
There's no river.
你能不能
Can you...
电话没电了
Phone's dead.
现在怎么办
Now what?
What now?
说话啊  我说真的
Come on. Seriously?
这是什么
What's this?
我正试着
I'm trying to
一点一点给电池充电
Trickle-charge the battery.
说真的吗
Seriously?
就这样转这东西
Just by turning that thing?
整流器
The commutator.
这也是发电机原理的一部分
It's the part which generates the electricity.
通常情况下  活塞发动机会转动它
Usually, this little piston engine turns it,
但是现在已经完全没用了
But considering it's lying here completely totaled...
无论如何
Anyway.
只能来点体力活了
Apply a little elbow grease...
会花很长时间的
It'll take longer.
很长时间
A lot longer.
但是理论上
But theoretically,
应该能行
It should work.
理论上
Theoretically.
必须得行
It has to work.
明白吗
You understand?
让我试试
Can I try?
要多久
How much longer?
我不知道
I don't know.
怀特老师
Mr. White?
你快不行了吗
You hanging in?
我很好
I'm good.
应该差不多了吧
It's got to be ready by now. Right?
再多摇一会儿
Give it a little longer,
保证我们能够
Just to make sure we're...
甲胺不会变质  是吗
Methylamine doesn't spoil, does it?
那不是我们来这里的原因吧
That's not why we're here.
对我撒谎了
Lie much?
快点摇
Push.
快点
Come on.
求你了
Please.
我为什么不直接去圣达菲呢
Why couldn't I have just gone to Santa Fe?
为什么
Why?
怀特老师
Mr. White?
你在干什么
What are you doing?
我的报应
I had this coming.
I have it coming.
我活该
I deserve this.
你会好起来的
You snap out of it.
你做的每件事都是为了你的家人
First off, everything you did, you did for your family.
对吗
Right?
我只是让他们更担心更失望  还有谎言
All I ever managed to do was worry and disappoint them and lie.
上帝啊
God.
所有的谎言
All the lies.
我都没法
I can't even...
我自己都不敢去想
I can't even keep them straight in my head anymore.
知道吗
You know what?
去他妈的  我要走着离开这里
Screw this. I'm walking.
你可以选择跟或不跟
You can come or not.
我另一只鞋呢
Where's my other shoe?
杰西 杰西
Jesse, Jesse
你现在处于低电解质的高危状态
Your body is running dangerously low on electrolytes.
钠  钾  钙
Sodium, potassium, calcium.
等到全部流失的时候
And when they're gone,
你的大脑就会停止指挥
Your brain ceases to communicate with your muscles.
你的肺就会停止呼吸
Your lungs stop breathing,
心脏会停止泵血
Your heart stops pumping.
你要是走出去
You go marching out there,
一小时内
And within an hour,
你就会死
You will be dead.
你立刻收起你那副可怜兮兮的样子
You need to cut out all your loser cry-baby crap right now
想点科学的点子出来
And think of something scientific!
科学的  是吗
Something scientific, right.
怎么了  快点
What? Come on.
你那么聪明
You're smart.
你从豆子里都能炼出毒品来
You made poison out of beans.
好吧  听着
All right, look.
这里我们有整个实验室
We got an entire lab right here.
我们把这些化学试剂加起来
All right? How about you take some of these chemicals
弄个什么火箭燃料
And mix up some rocket fuel?
至少能发个信号什么的
That way, you can just send up a signal flare.
要么你造个机器人帮我们
Or you make some kind of robot to get us help,
要么弄个自动追踪系统
Or a homing device or...
或者造个新电池
Build a new battery or...
等等
Wait. No.
不如我们把车上的东西拆下来
What if we just take some stuff off of the RV
造一个不一样的车出来
And build it into something completely different?
像是沙漠越野车什么的
Like a dune buggy.
那样的话  我们至少能越野了
That way, we can just dune buggy...
怎么了
What is it?
What?
你有钱吗
Do you have any money?
-零钱  硬币  -我有一堆
- Change, I mean. Coins. - I got a bunch of them.
收集起来
Then gather them.
还有那些金属垫圈  螺丝  螺栓  钉子
And washers and nuts and bolts and screws
各种各样的金属零件
And whatever little pieces of metal
只要是镀锌的都行
We can think of that is galvanized.
必须镀锌的  或者本身就是纯锌的
It has to be galvanized or solid zinc.
-纯锌的  好  -帮我把刹车垫拿来
- Solid zinc, right. - And bring me brake pads.
前轮应该有的
The front wheels should have discs.
拆下来给我
Take them off and bring them to me.
刹车垫
Brake pads.
-我们要造什么  -你自己说的
- What are we building? - You said it yourself.
机器人吗
A robot?
电池
A battery.
快去
Move!
跟我见过的所有电池都不一样
This doesn't look like any battery I ever saw.
相信我  这就是电池
Well, trust me. It is a battery.
或者说  是原电池
Or rather, one cell of a battery.
给  把海绵剪成两半
Here. Cut up the last two sponges.
还记得电解质吗
Remember the electrolytes?
动动脑子
Think about it.
电池其实也就是原电池
A battery is a galvanic cell.
也就是阳极和阴极
It's no more than an anode and a cathode
离子在电解液里分开
Separated by an electrolyte, right?
-没错  -不管怎么样
- Right. - Well, anyway.
一极我们用氧化汞
On one side, we have mercuric oxide
还有刹车垫上的石墨
And graphite from your brake pads.
组成阴极
This is the cathode.
也就是电池的正极
This is the positive terminal.
电流就是从那里出来的
This is where the supply of current flows out from.
然后
Then...
看我做  另外一边就是我们的阳极
Here, I'll show you. On the opposite side is our anode.
这个
This...
是锌的
It's zinc.
就是我们找到的硬币和所有镀锌的东西
It's what we find in our coins and anything galvanized.
海绵就是电解液吗
So, the sponge is the electrolyte?
不  氢氧化钾是电解液
No, the potassium hydroxide is the electrolyte.
也对  这就是为什么我要用海绵去吸
But yes, that's what I'm soaking the sponges in.
不错
Good.
很好  现在
Good. And now,
我们要用什么来传导电流呢
What shall we use to conduct this beautiful current with?
想到了什么元素
What one particular element comes to mind?
一根电线
A wire.
是铜
Copper.
-我是说  -是铜
- Well, I mean... - It's copper.
唯一的问题是需要多少这样的原电池单元
The only question now is will this supply enough current?
我们要做多少
And how many cells will we need?
我们的材料应该够做六个
Maybe we've only got material enough for six.
-要把盖子盖上吗  -等等
- Put the lid on. - Wait.
正极
Positive.
阴极
Cathode.
阳极
Anode.
妈的
Damn.
非常好
That is good.
非常好  我们去试试
That's very good. Here we go.
怎么样
How's the...
很好
It's fine.
我知道我可以信任你
I know I can trust you to...
不管发生什么
Whatever happens,
你家人会得到你那份的
Your family will get your share.
谢谢
Thank you.
那么
So...
我等你的消息
I'll be hearing from you.
大家最近怎么样
How's everyone doing?
孩子会不会现在就出世
Is that baby ever going to come out, you think?
-我知道过了预产期了  -只是玩笑
- I know, enough already. It's... - I'm teasing.
要来的总会来
Everything in its time.
沃尔特  我已经看了你的扫描结果
Walt, I have your scan results.
有病症减退的迹象
And you're showing signs of remission.
我的天哪
My God.
我要解释一下
I want to clarify.
对于症状减退的情况存在误解
There are some misconceptions about what remission signifies.
不是说病人完全治愈
It does not mean that the patient is cured.
说某人处于症状消退期
To classify someone as in remission,
我们必须确认肿瘤没有长大的迹象
We only need to determine that the tumor hasn't grown.
肿瘤没有生长吗  上帝啊
That it hasn't grown? Jesus.
学术上来说
Technically speaking,
即使病人处在症状消退期
A tumor can remain the exact same size it was before
肿瘤还是有可能维持原来的大小
And the patient could still be in remission.
在沃尔特的病例  处于癌症的第三阶段
Now, in Walt's case, with a stage 3 adenocarcinoma,
我预期看到  至少
I like to see... I hope to see at least
肿瘤组织会有25%到35%的减少
A 25 to 35% reduction in tumor mass,
事实证明理疗已经对癌细胞起了作用
Something to tell me that the cancer has responded to the therapy.
大家还在听吗
Everybody still with me?
结果怎么样
And how has my cancer responded?
沃尔特  你的肿瘤组织已经减少了80%
Walt,Your tumor has shrunk by 80%.
-我的天哪  -等等  我真的
- My God. - Wait, I'm sorry. I'm really...
我不太懂  80%是很多吗
I'm confused. Isn't 80% a lot?
妈妈  当然
Mom. Yeah.
80%是很多很多
80% is a lot.
-好的  但是我  -亲爱的  你是对的
- Okay, but, I'm... - Sweetheart, you were right.
-真的是好消息  -真的是好消息
- It's very good news. - It's very good news.
你在开玩笑吗
Are you kidding me?
我差点就想出去了  现在峰回路转了
Just when I try to get out, they pull me back in.
不过你的咳嗽是我们要讨论的
Now, that cough is the other thing we need to discuss.
沃尔特  根据扫描结果  你患有放射性肺炎
According to your scan, Walt, you have radiation pneumonitis.
没关系  这很平常
It's okay. This is fairly common.
看见里面那个吓人的东西了吗
See that scary-looking thing there?
那是组织炎症  是放射治疗的副反应
That's tissue inflammation. That's a reaction to your radio therapy.
通常不是很严重  但是会导致你那样的咳嗽
It's usually not serious, but it can produce a cough like that.
我会给你开点强的松[肾上腺素药物]
I'll prescribe some prednisone.
组织炎症
Tissue inflammation?
你确定吗
Are you sure about that?
因为有一天  我咳出了血
Because the other day, I was coughing up some blood.
-什么  -可能
- What? - You probably have a tear
由于咳嗽引起了食道撕裂  那是相当严重的
In your esophagus from the coughing, and that can be very serious.
你会因为流血过多而亡的
You could rupture and bleed to death.
你今天走之前  我们会处理一下这个问题
We're going to have to deal with that before you leave here today.
等一下  什么时候的事  为什么不告诉我
Wait a minute. When did this happen? Why didn't you tell me?
-对不起  我  -不要再隐瞒  沃尔特
- I'm sorry. I... - No more secrets, Walt.
发生那样的情况  你必须马上通知我
With something like this, you have to call me. Immediately.
从检查结果看来  我们还未完全脱离危险
Now, with these results, we're not completely out of the woods.
但至少我们现在多了些选择
But now at least we have some options.
最关键的就是时间
The most important of which is time.
接下来几周  我们还要进一步讨论
We'll have more to discuss in the next few weeks.
但是现在  你们一家人应该好好庆祝一下
But for now, I'd say that you folks have earned some celebrating.
太棒了
Yes.
上帝啊
Oh, my God.